KAMARA REYNOLDS

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

reynoldskamara@soulsitescoding.com > 516-668-2866 > Coral Springs, FL <u>LinkedIn</u> > <u>GitHub</u> > <u>Portfolio</u>

Full stack developer with **1 year plus** freelance experience seeking a position in software engineering. A mixture of analytical skills and artistic creativity will be a great fit to the right company. An asset to any team with the ability to lead and follow. The right combination of focus, encouragement, and drive will help uplift the workspace and keep everyone on task.

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, Next.js, MUI,

Bootstrap, SQLalchemy, Sequelize

DATABASES: SQLite, Postgres

TOOLS: VSCode, Docker, Vite, Render, Vercel

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE DEVELOPMENT >> Web Developer > Remote > React, Next.js, MUI

October 2022 - Current

- Designed responsive sites customized to clients' specific needs with backend capabilities if required.
- Increased the visibility of businesses by adding an online presence to their company.

DATA ANNOTATION >> Al Trainer > Remote > JavaScript, Python

October 2023 - Current

- Train AI to provide correct responses to programming questions writing detailed notes critiquing responses.
- Improved multiple program-focused AI to handle complex algorithms and multi-page applications.

ACV TECHS >> HVAC Technician > Margate, FL

October 2021 - March 2024

- Troubleshot and repaired fixtures providing detailed descriptions to clients with fair prices and swift completion.
- Learned the craft quickly, receiving my own truck and servicing clients on my own after a short time.

MATER BEACH ACADEMY & CARVER MIDDLE SCHOOL >> Math Teacher > Surf Side-Delray, FL January 2017 – June 2021

- Worked with lower students providing custom lessons starting at their skill level keeping a detailed record of progress.
- Raised their average scores by one to two letter grades by finding areas of improvement more efficiently.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

SOUL ACADEMY >> **School Portal App** > React, Redux, Flask, SQLAlchemy

GitHub > App

- Developed an interactive grade book using React.js to supply teacher users the flexibility to create and edit assignments and grade in an easy-to-use interface.
- Utilized Flask and Redux to establish a dual-login system where user dashboard and site access are determined by whether the user is teacher or student.
- Implemented full CRUD capabilities to class, assignment, and grade tables using Flask blueprint routing API to make calls to the SQL tables and WT Forms to validate table data.

HONEY STOCK >> **Stock Trading App** > React, Redux, Flask, SQLAlchemy

GitHub > App

- Introduced real-time stock data utilizing Polygon Stock API and ReactChart.js to supply stock information to the stock info page with an up-to-date chart displaying the history of a given stock's price over a period of time.
- Designed a dynamic dashboard using SLQAlchemy and Redux to populate based on user specific data to portfolio and watchlist stocks.

SEW POSH >> Upholstery Website > React, Next.js, MUI

GitHub > App

- Created a reviews page using Elf Sight to embed a widget with overall ratings, current reviews, and the option to add a review.
- Utilized Next.js and MUI and to introduce interactive and dynamic gallery pages where pictures are populated based on the category which can be viewed in a slideshow and in full screen.

EDUCATION

APP ACADEMY >> Full Stack Web Development

Completed January 2024

Completed December 2015